WILLIAM DINIZ

CLOUD/BACKEND ENGINEER

INFO

PHONE

+55(11)98402-8886

EMAIL

wrkdiniz@gmail.com

LINKS

http://www.icedburn.com

Linkedin

SKILLS

Amazon AWS

Cloud

CI/CD

C# .NET

.NET Core

Docker

NoSQL

SQL

Python

Ruby

Git

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

• • • • •

English

Spanish; Castilian

• • • 0 0

Norwegian

• 0 0 0 0

HOBBIES

PROFILE

Early adopter and passionate for breaking limits (Trail Runner) in love for the challenges that the IT Cloud and Backend development offers! Experience in building, migrating and maintaining high availability systems like McDonald's e-commerce platform on AWS and in breaking big monoliths into micro services. Please, feel free to visit my virtual resume/portfolio on www.icedburn.com.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Technical Development Coordinator, Tapps Games

São Paulo

Jul 2019 — Present

Coordinate priorities and lead team activities, also acting as a Tech Lead. I had to to work closely with the manager to plan and manage team hours and effort, also pair with the Product Owner to define the team priorities and work side-by-side with the team leading the technical decisions and helping them to develop themselves.

Software Development Coordinator, RDI

São Paulo

Jan 2019 — Jun 2019

RDI is the main supplier of McDonald's technologies like the restaurant software, cloud solutions and the e-commerce platform. I had coordinate and lead the team that build the Order and Totalize micro services during the transformation project where we did a reengineering of our e-commerce monolith solution to a micro services based solution. I helped to organize the team and deliveries and also making them comfortable with the new technologies that we were adopting at that time.

Developer, RDI

São Paulo

Mar 2016 — Jan 2019

I had started on RDI as a Junior Developer on 2016 and receive one promotion per year until became a Senior Developer on 2018 and Coordinator on 2019. As a developer I had worked mainly on production maintenance and market adoption/localization of the McDonald's e-commerce platform. I worked as main developer in some of the important projects (like the introduction of the app Order feature on US market, connecting 14k physical stores to our application in the Cloud). My deliveries and stakeholders management skills was always praised by the leadership giving me 2 individual prizes (Unsung Hero and Innovation trofies) and also some Team Awards with the team.

Technical Consultant, CTM/SP (Navy)

São Paulo

Jan 2014 — Mar 2016

R&D Team to develop the nuclear reactor Human Machine Interface of the first Brazilian nuclear submarine produced and developed in Brazil.

Engineer Intern, ABB

Osasco

Jan 2013 — Dec 2013

I really love to take part in some races, specially Trail Run. I also like to play some games like LoL, Horizon Zero Dawn and others. Although it was an engineer internship, it was there that I first had contact with backend development. I worked in 2 main projects as intern: The ABB Asset Vista, working in the family navigation library and its integration of the other screens and also in the ABB Fingerprint that generate reports for industrial plants.

EDUCATION

Electrical Engineering, Escola Politécnica da USP

São Paulo

Feb 2008 — Dec 2013

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Jun 2020 — Jun 2023

AWARDS

Unsung Hero

RDI

Aug 2017 — Aug 2017

Innovation Award

RDI

USP

Sep 2017 — Sep 2017

Best Graduation Project of Electrical Engineering (Control & Automation)

Dec 2012 — Dec 2012

RECOMMENDATIONS

Audrey Tom

Former McDonald's Director of US IT Restaurant Solutions

Jun 2018 — Jun 2018

I highly recommend William! William helped us deploy Mobile Ordering to 14,000 restaurants in the US. In order to accomplish this, there was a heavy data migration effort which included late nights, perseverance, patience, and just plain hard work. Without William's help, we would not have been able to accomplish this goal!

William loves to learn, and absorbs new topics like a sponge. He loves challenges, and takes them on with passion, creativity, and a go-gettem' attitude. He is a great addition to any team. He is a strong team player, friendly, seeks to learn, happy to share knowledge with others, has a positive attitude, and enjoys a good laugh. William provided me and my team A+ service and was extremely responsive. I appreciated William because he took the time to explain things, and translated complex technical concepts into easier, more user-friendly language so that anyone could understand. He was always dependable!